[
    {
        "question": "1. How many moles HCL will be required to react with potassium heptaoxodichromate (VI) to produce 3 moles of chlorine?", 
        "optionA": "14", 
        "optionB": "12", 
        "optionC": "11",
        "optionD": "10",
        "answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Which of the following noble gases is commonly found in the atmosphere?", 
        "optionA": "Xenon", 
        "optionB": "Neon", 
        "optionC": "Helium",
        "optionD": "Argon",
        "answer": "Argon" 
    },
    {
        "question": "3. An efflorescent compound is a substance that?",
        "optionA": "absorbs water froom the air without dissolving in i",
        "optionB": "is capable of giving off coloured luminosity",
        "optionC": "gives out water to the atmosphere",
        "optionD": "gives out its water of crystallization on heating",
        "answer": "gives out water to the atmosphere"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. A molar solution of caustic soda is prepared by dissolving",
        "optionA": "40 g NaOH in 100 g of water",
        "optionB": "40 g NaOH in 1000 g of water",
        "optionC": "20 g NaOH in 500 of solution",
        "optionD": "20 g NaOH in 1000 g of solution",
        "answer": "40 g NaOH in 1000 g of water"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Bees inject an acidic substance when they sting. Which of the following chemical could be used to treat bee stings?",
        "optionA": "CH3COOH",
        "optionB": "NaHCO3",
        "optionC": "C2H5OH",
        "optionD": "H2O2",
        "answer": "NaHCO3"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. The following substances are examples of addition polymer except",
        "optionA": "nylon",
        "optionB": "perspex",
        "optionC": "polyethene",
        "optionD": "polychloroethene",
        "answer": "nylon"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. The energy value of petrol can be determined by",
        "optionA": "Bomb calorimeter",
        "optionB": "Catalytic cracker",
        "optionC": "Fractionating column",
        "optionD": "Thermometer",
        "answer": "Fractionating column"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. The dissolution of common salt in water is a physical change because",
        "optionA": "the salt can be obtained by crystallization",
        "optionB": "the solution will not boil at 100 Degrees",
        "optionC": "heat is not generated during mixing",
        "optionD": "the salt can be recovered by the evaporation of water",
        "answer": "the salt can be recovered by the evaporation of wate"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Hydrogen is not liberated when trioxonitrate(v)acid reacts with zinc because",
        "optionA": "zinc is not rendered passive by acid",
        "optionB": "trioxonitrate(v)acid is a strong acid",
        "optionC": "all nitrates are soluble in wate",
        "optionD": "oxides of nitrogen are produced",
        "answer": "trioxonitrate(v)acid is a strong acid"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. In a neutralization reaction involving HCI and NaOH using litmus as indicator, the colour at the end point is",
        "optionA": "Blue",
        "optionB": "Red",
        "optionC": "Orange",
        "optionD": "Purple",
        "answer": "Purple"
    }
]